<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[IndyRB.org]]></title>
  <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-09-27T15:49:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://indyrb.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[The Indianapolis Ruby Brigade]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup September 13, 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/09/13/meetup-september13/"/>
    <updated>2017-09-13T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/09/13/meetup-september13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Lightning Panel!</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zMnFZz3sYZQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h3>Topics:</h3>

<ul>
<li>What is important to me when looking for a job?</li>
<li>What is important to me when looking to hire?</li>
<li>What code lesson could you have learned early in your career that would&rsquo;ve saved you a ton of pain?</li>
<li>What gem do you keep returning to, time and time again? i.e. a long-lived, super useful, under-the-radar thing.</li>
<li>What is your favorite non-standard pattern to apply to a Rails project?</li>
<li>When do you open source your code? How do you keep up with managing it?</li>
</ul>


<h3>Panelists:</h3>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/stevehodgesindy">Steve Hodges</a></p>

<p>Steve is a full-time rubyist and director of technology at Localstake, an Indy-based financial startup. He&rsquo;s written web apps since 1999, switching to primarily working in Ruby on Rails work in 2011.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/claytron">Clayton Parker</a></p>

<p>Clayton is the DevOps wizard at Octiv, where he got his professional start in Ruby. When he&rsquo;s not hacking away in Vim, you&rsquo;ll find him on the soccer field or drinking a craft beer somewhere around town.</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/ar3_me">Andrew Robinson III</a></p>

<p>Andrew is the head of product and engineering at Lessonly. He started out doing Net and Java (even some COBOL back in the high school days)&hellip; but found the light around 2011 which is when he found RoR. He loves engineering, but recently his passions have been split between engineering, design, product, and servant leadership.</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/annamul">Anna Carey</a></p>

<p>Anna is a Team Lead/Senior Developer for MOBI and has been programming in Ruby since 2007.  She likes DevOps and performance work far more than UI. Before that, she wrote java for the NCAA. She has two adorable goofball daughters that are 1 and 5.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/t27duck">Tony Drake</a></p>

<p>A senior web developer with about 10 years (most of it in Ruby) of total experience building web sites professionally. By day, he curses DHH&rsquo;s name while hacking away at code and trying to keep junior devs from scraping their knees. By night, he&rsquo;s peeling away from the starting line while blowing up other vehicles in his way in Mario Kart.</p>

<h3>Resources:</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://dilbert.com/">Dilbert</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0020/">The Zen of Python</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.sandimetz.com/99bottles/sample/#_shameless_green">Sandi Metz - Shameless Green</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.engineyard.com/blog/keeping-your-rails-controllers-dry-with-services">Service Objects (POROs)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/activemodel-form-objects">Form Objects</a></li>
<li><a href="https://semaphoreci.com/community/tutorials/how-to-reduce-controller-bloat-with-interactors-in-ruby">Interactor pattern</a></li>
<li><a href="https://practicingruby.com/articles/creational-design-patterns#factory-method">Factory Pattern</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mperham/sidekiq">Sidekiq</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/resque/resque">Resque</a></li>
<li><a href="http://haml.info/">Haml Comments</a></li>
<li><a href="https://activeadmin.info/">ActiveAdmin</a></li>
<li><a href="http://pryrepl.org/">Pry</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/activerecord-hackery/squeel">Squeel</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elabs/pundit">Pundit</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/dejan/rails_panel">Rails Panel</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/flyerhzm/bullet">Bullet</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/cldwalker/hirb">Hirb</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup August 9, 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/08/09/meetup-august9/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-09T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/08/09/meetup-august9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/nic_ollis">Nic Ollis</a> - GraphQL and You</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-TaqAcPQ1Jk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Nic provides a beginners intro into <a href="http://graphql.org/">GraphQL</a>. How its compares to REST, as well how easy it is to get it integrated into your existing Rails project with a small tutorial on adding a query operation to a web app.</p>

<p>Nic Ollis is a Software Engineer at <a href="https://www.clustertruck.com/">ClusterTruck</a>. He primarily focuses on creating amazing software using Rails and React, with interest in moving over into machine learning in the near future. You can find out about his past and current projects at <a href="http://ollis.me/">http://ollis.me</a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://indyrb.github.io/assets/20170809/GraphQL%20and%20You.pdf">Slides</a></li>
<li><a href="http://graphql.org/">GraphQL</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rmosolgo/graphql-ruby">GraphQL-Ruby Gem</a></li>
<li><a href="http://bit.ly/indy_rb_otter">Otter (example Rails project with GraphQL)</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup July 12, 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/07/12/meetup-july12/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-12T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/07/12/meetup-july12</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/panozzaj">Anthony Panozzo</a> - Sidekiq</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6cihVOlBoes" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>In this presentation, you&rsquo;ll learn about why you might want to consider an asynchronous worker queue for your web application. We&rsquo;ll talk about some Ruby frameworks for doing so, and then cover Sidekiq in depth. We&rsquo;ll start with basic usage and testing of Sidekiq jobs. To provide more context, we will run through a quick overview of Redis (which Sidekiq is built on) and what it can be used for. Finally, we will explore some useful Sidekiq Pro extensions and point out some important things to watch out for.</p>

<p>Who is Anthony?</p>

<p>Hi, I&rsquo;m Anthony Panozzo. I work as a Senior Software Engineer at OurHealth, and have used Sidekiq on a couple of different projects over the last few years. One time I woke up and had a million jobs in a queue and was very concerned.</p>

<h3><a href="http://occameducation.com/about/leadership/">Daniel Brown</a> - WTF is Motivation?</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mzH6dMiBvkk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Ennui, lethargy and lassitude are fancy words often used to describe a basic problem: Person A doesn’t like doing Thing B and feels an obvious lack of enthusiasm &hellip; but Thing B is kind of important. In other words, no one calls you lazy because you didn’t create a temporary fork-and-spoon sculpture using your new cutlery. You get called lazy when you are supposed to do something that is important to somebody &hellip; and you don’t.</p>

<p>This talk is all about Self-Determination Theory (SDT), a psychological model that describes motivation as coming from autonomy, competency and relevance. My aim is to teach you to use SDT to build internal motivation when it doesn&rsquo;t come naturally and teach others to do the same.</p>

<p>Who is Daniel?</p>

<p>I (Daniel Brown) am a husband (to Nina), co-founder (of Occam Education) and code monkey (Rails!) in roughly that order. I studied Arabic and Russian as an undergrad, went to Syria and then dropped out of an MS program in Arabic to start Occam Education with my brother. In 2014, I went to a Rails coding bootcamp, and in 2016, I received an MS in Applied Positive Psychology. I have worked in education (tutoring and ESL) since 2005, and much of my recent work has been in coaching adolescents striving to build internal motivation and grit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup June 14, 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/06/14/meetup-june14/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-14T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/06/14/meetup-june14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/t27duck">Tony Drake</a> - Testing a Gem Against Different Databases and Different Versions of Rails</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7H6AiL7Hi7I" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>So you built a gem that integrates with ActiveRecord. You write tests, push to Github, CI passes, and then publish to RubyGems. Great! But later, someone submits a bug&hellip; the gem doesn&rsquo;t work with MySQL and Rails 4.2 and you only tested your gem against PostgreSQL and Rails 5. You want your gem to support all &ldquo;active&rdquo; versions of Rails and at least both PostgreSQL and MySQL. So how to do you it? How do you get your tests to be able to run against different versions of Rails and databases on a whim? Let&rsquo;s go through from start to finish the story of creating a gem and testing against these permutations of real world setups.</p>

<p>Tony Drake is a senior web developer with about 10 years (most of it in Ruby) of total experience building sites professionally. By day, He curses DHH&rsquo;s name while hacking away at code. By night, he&rsquo;s peeling away from the starting line while blowing up other vehicles in my way in Mario Kart.</p>

<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/chris_vannoy">Chris Vannoy</a> - Scripting the Mac with Ruby</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/owXhe4mKqwc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Ruby’s a scripting language, so why not use it for, you know, scripting. When you combine MacOS’s built-in scripting and automation tools - such as Automator, launchd, AppleScript, Workflows and Services - with Ruby, nothing is out of reach. Let’s walk through MacOS’ core automation and scripting tools, and use a dash of Ruby to build ourselves something useful (or, failing that, something silly).</p>

<p>Chris has been developing in Ruby for more than a decade, is a former instructor at The Iron Yard coding bootcamp, and current Senior Engineer at Sigtsr. He cares entirely too much about college football, naps, and podcasts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup March 8, 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/02/08/meetup-march-8/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-08T21:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/02/08/meetup-march-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/t27duck">Tony Drake</a> - Reporting on Rails - ActiveRecord and ROLAP Working Together</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L1E8cKWCEtU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>This talk is over a brief journey through the world of Relational Online Analytical Processing (ROLAP) and seeing how this can apply to Rails. This will also include a couple database considerations and possibly an overview of a DSL he&rsquo;s building that ties it all together.</p>

<p>Tony Drake is currently senior developer on a team specializing in billing and reporting for an enterprise-level Rails application where he co-architected a custom ROLAP framework using PostgreSQL on the backend. He&rsquo;d like to share his ten years (seven of those with Rails) of professional web development experience with others.  He can also kick anyone&rsquo;s butt in Mario Kart with Rosalina.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/t27duck/showandtell/tree/master/presentations/indyrb/2017-03">Slides</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/t27duck/active_reporting">Active Reporting Gem</a></li>
<li><a href="http://railsconf.com/program#session-130">Link to this Session at upcoming RailsConf 2017!</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/rydertimberlake">Ryder Timberlake</a> - Expand Your Perspective and Change Your Life Through Pair Programming</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LEHqhp1-zNQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><em><em>Editor&rsquo;s Note:</em> This video is highly condensed for time and has poor audio due to many people speaking simultaneously. That said, I think it&rsquo;s a wonderful example of how to run an impromptu meetup workshop, and a view into the thought and processes of solving a few simple puzzles on Codewars.</em></p>

<p>Tech is siloed. Languages, teams, and services are siloed. Good design is frequently portrayed and interpreted as a constellation of context-independent best practices. And oftentimes we can hardly have a productive conversation about design without our knee-jerk ideas of the way we ought to build something getting in the way.<br/>
When we enforce conventions in a project, we often do so without a good understanding of which conventions are essential and which are peripheral. We often do so without a sufficiently shared vocabulary of design with which to argue constructively. And when we choose a tool, we often do so by merely defaulting to what we know behind a shield of inscrutable buzzwords &ndash; words whose meaning is rarely exposed to the same rigorous inquiry with which we examine spaces or tabs or choice of editor.</p>

<p>I would argue that a startling majority of the most intractable technical problems we face in software are simply interpersonal and communication problems expressing themselves in a technical domain. And I think we can make things a whole lot better by just putting our heads together.</p>

<p>This is more workshop than talk. Bring your laptop and ideally your free <a href="https://www.codewars.com">Codewars account</a>.</p>

<p>Ryder is an Iron Yard alumnus and engineer at Salesforce, where he writes tests for the Approvals app and is a contributor to the automated testing framework used across the Marketing Cloud. He is an outspoken advocate of sound implementations of pair programming, which he believes to holistically aid all manner of technical and human endeavors in software &ndash; from writing maintainable code and fostering good user experiences to encouraging effective communication and diversity in the workplace.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.codewars.com/kata/57cebe1dc6fdc20c57000ac9">Codewars kata: Shortest Word</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.codewars.com/kata/511f11d355fe575d2c000001">CodeWars kata: 2 Oldest Ages</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.greaterthancode.com/podcast/episode-022-you-are-an-asset/">Ryder on Greater Than Code podcast: &ldquo;You Are an Asset&rdquo;</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup February 8, 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/02/08/meetup-february-8/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-08T21:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/02/08/meetup-february-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/nullvoxpopuli">L. Preston Sego III</a> - My App is Too Big - Architecting for the Lazy</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/23o94WPDqCg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/18qV3IXbjfIeEFhEarpJBbjLqVEAV9e83RIzycWgdSFs/edit#slide=id.p">Slides</a></li>
<li><a href="http://github.com/nullvoxpopuli/drawers">Drawers Gem</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/armzilla82">Seth Baughman</a> - The Rails Router - How it do</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Phhsyoyp6_E" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.fretless.com/rails-router-how-it-do/">Blog Post - The Rails Router: How it do</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup January 11, 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/01/11/meetup-january-11/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-11T21:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2017/01/11/meetup-january-11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/milamsoft">Aaron Milam</a> - Building a Gem</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qb76cAfSoIo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://guides.rubygems.org/make-your-own-gem">Rubygems.org - Make You Own Gem Guide</a></li>
<li><a href="http://bundler.io/v1.14/man/bundle-gem.1.html">How to use Bundler&rsquo;s built-in gem generator and tools</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/t27duck">Tony Drake</a> - Totally not Thrown Together PSQL Talk #84</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NCZN6I-crmo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup September 14, 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/09/14/meetup-september-14/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-14T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/09/14/meetup-september-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/t27duck">Tony Drake</a> - Arbitrary Multi Tenant Configuration for <strike>Fun</strike> and Profit</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U_u2w7qNRWg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/t27duck/showandtell/tree/master/presentations/indyrb/2016-09">Slides</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/chris_vannoy">Chris Vannoy</a> - A Simple Plan: Building a Small Web API in Something New</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BY8W7owgMEI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/dummied/a-simple-plan">Slides</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup August 10, 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/08/10/meetup-august-10/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-10T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/08/10/meetup-august-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/netshade">Chris Zelenak</a> - So You Have to Build Some Analytics</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tLE_Z4rqGjs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://scaleassembly.com/indy-rb-analytics.pdf">Slides</a></li>
<li><a href="http://scaleassembly.com/">Scale Assembly</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HyperLogLog">HyperLogLog</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.acqualia.com/soulver/">SoulVer</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/chris_vannoy">Chris Vannoy</a> - Stupid ActiveRecord Tricks</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/em6LYcQsEJo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/tree/master/activerecord">ActiveRecord</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup June 8th, 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/06/08/meetup-june-8/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-08T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/06/08/meetup-june-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/plamere">Paul Lamere</a> - Data Mining Music</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f7XN3RuDzmc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://confreaks.tv/videos/railsconf2016-closing-keynote-paul-lamere">Confreaks - Closing Keynote: Paul Lamere</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.spotify.com/us/">Spotify</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup May 11, 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/05/11/meetup-may-11/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-11T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/05/11/meetup-may-11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/jheth">Joe Heth</a> - Bundler</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BPX9adQCRvM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://bundler.io/">Bundler</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup April 13, 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/04/13/meetup-april-13/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-13T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/04/13/meetup-april-13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/ajporterfield">Andrew Porterfield</a> - Incorporating SMS into your Rails app using Twilio</h3>

<script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="1bed27c4a983489c8bd0c22d73feecaf" data-ratio="1.77777777777778" src="//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script>


<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.twilio.com/">Twilio</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.evrconnect.com/">evrconnect</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ajporterfield/indyrb_apr_2016_twilio">Code from the talk</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup February 10, 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/02/10/meetup-february-10/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-10T21:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/02/10/meetup-february-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/jheth">Joe Heth</a> - Mutation Testing</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ngv0GXjWSc0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://mutation-station.r15.railsrumble.com/">Mutation Station</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mutation_testing">WikiPedia - Mutation Testing</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mbj/mutant">Mutant Gem</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/amalc/rubyzoho">RubyZoho</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/claytron">Clayton Parker</a> - Exploring Code with Pry</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G32gcUXZAw0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/claytron/pry-talk">Slides Code</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/claytron/exploring-code-with-pry">Slides and Notes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://pryrepl.org">Pry-Repl website</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup January 13, 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/01/13/meetup-january-13/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-13T21:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2016/01/13/meetup-january-13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/stevegrossi">Steve Grossi</a> - Ruby News</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://work.stevegrossi.com/2016/01/14/new-features-in-ruby-2-3/">New Features in Ruby 2.3</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/joelmeador">Joel Meador</a> - Action Cable</h3>

<p><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2016-01-13_Joel_Meador-Action_Cable.mp4">Video</a> (46m : 6s)</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/expectedbehavior/indyrb-actioncable">Code</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/tree/master/actioncable">Action Cable (source repo)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/n0WUjGkDFS0">Action Cable Introduction from rubyonrails.org</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup October 14, 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/10/14/meetup-october-14/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-14T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/10/14/meetup-october-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/duncanson50">Matt Duncan</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/1bertlol">Adam Darrah</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/davecornelius">David Cornelius</a> - Brackets for Good: A Nonprofit Rails app that Processes over $1M in Donations Annually</h3>

<p><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-10-14_Brackets_for_Good/2015-10-14_Brackets_for_Good.mp4">Video</a> (26m : 41s)</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-10-14_Brackets_for_Good/BFG%20Introduction%202016%20Indy%20RB.pdf">Slides: Brackets for Good Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-10-14_Brackets_for_Good/Brackets%20For%20Good%20Development.pdf">Slides: Brackets for Good Development</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/v/NiDGTprVJu4?start=49&amp;end=100&amp;version=3">Starcraft: Epic Moments of All Time clip (0:49-1:40)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://bfg.org/">Brackets for Good</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/davecornelius">David Cornelius</a> - React with Rails (in Brackets for Good)</h3>

<p><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-10-14_Brackets_for_Good/">Video</a> (1h : 12m)</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-10-14_Brackets_for_Good/rails+react_landscape.pdf">Slides</a></li>
<li><a href="https://facebook.github.io/react/">ReactJS</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup September 9, 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/09/20/meetup-september-9/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-20T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/09/20/meetup-september-9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/matthewrnewell">Matt Newell</a> - How to Parse Excel with Ruby</h3>

<p><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-09-09_Matt_Newell_-_How_to_Parse_Excel_with_Ruby.mp4">Video</a> (17m : 31s)</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-09-09_Matt_Newell_-_How_to_Parse_Excel_with_Ruby.pdf">Slides</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/matthewnewell/vet">Parse Excel Github Repository</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Little-Book-Talent-Improving/dp/034553025X">The Little Book of Talent</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/roo-rb/roo">Roo</a></li>
<li><a href="http://pryrepl.org/">pry</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/randym/axlsx">AXSLX</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/dstrus">Davey Strus</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/chris_vannoy">Chris Vannoy</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/barnes7td">Timothy Barnes</a> - Panel: Teaching Ruby</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yb0EpP2xFe4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup August 12, 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/07/12/meetup-august-12/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-12T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/07/12/meetup-august-12</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/_swanson">Matt Swanson</a> - Negativity Bias in Written Communication (How to not Accidentally be an Asshole)</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sTlLfGZQEOA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/c67wwqy0igekkg4/negativity-bias.pdf?dl=0">Slides</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PJjmw9TRB7s">Derek Prior - Implementing a Strong Code-Review Culture (RailsConf 2015)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/bbatsov/rubocop">Rubocop</a></li>
<li><a href="http://phinze.github.io/2013/12/08/pairing-vs-code-review.html">Pairing vs Code Review</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://twitter.com/ar3_me">Andrew L Robinson III</a> - An API Journey</h3>

<p><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-08-12_Andrew%20Robinson%20III%20-%20An%20API%20Journey.mp4">Video</a> (43m : 46s)</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://prezi.com/mkwcvhrs6rjp/an-api-journey/">Prezi Slides</a></li>
<li><a href="http://stateless.co/hal_specification.html">JSON-HAL</a></li>
<li><a href="http://jsonapi.org/">JSON-API</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ruby-grape/grape">Grape</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/nesquena/rabl">Rabl</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rails/jbuilder">jbuilder</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rails-api/active_model_serializers">ActiveModel::Serializers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apotonick/roar">ROAR</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apotonick/trailblazer">Trailblazer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/cerebris/jsonapi-resources">jsonapi-resources</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup July 8, 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/07/08/meetup-july-8/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-08T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/07/08/meetup-july-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/stevegrossi">Steve Grossi</a> - Ruby News</h3>

<p><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-07-08_Steve_Grossi-Ruby_News.mp3">Audio</a> (3m : 48s)</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://railsconf.com/">RailsConf</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.engineyard.com/2015/a-look-at-rails-5">Rails 5</a></li>
<li><a href="http://weblog.rubyonrails.org/2015/6/16/Rails-3-2-22-4-1-11-and-4-2-2-have-been-released-and-more">Security Updates to Rails</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rubysec/bundler-audit">Bundler-Audit</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.reddotrubyconf.com/">RedDotRubyConf</a></li>
<li><a href="http://5by5.tv/changelog/161">The ChangeLog - Ilia Gegorick - HTTP/2</a></li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://twitter.com/mileszs">Miles Sterrett</a> - How do we Learn Best? (group discussion)</h3>

<p><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-07-08_Miles_Sterrett-How_Do_We_Learn_Best.mp3">Audio</a> (1h : 28m)</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nostarch.com/rubywizardry">Ruby Wizardry</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.opensourcerails.com/">OpenSourceRails</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.epicodus.com/">Epicodus</a></li>
<li><a href="http://exercism.io/">Exercism.io</a></li>
<li><a href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/sandi-metz-rules-for-developers">Sandi Metz Rules for Developers</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup June 10, 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/06/10/meetup-june-10/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-10T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/06/10/meetup-june-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/joelmeador">Joel Meador</a> - Elixir</h3>

<p>Links:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://joelmeador.tumblr.com/post/106523542367/fizzbuzz-elixir-edition">FizzBuzz, Elixir Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="http://joelmeador.tumblr.com/post/116837714087/roman-numeral-conversion-in-elixir">Roman Numeral conversion in Elixir</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.selectedintelligence.com/post/116327140769/parallel-map-in-elixir">Parallel Map in Elixir</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5kYmOyJjGDM&amp;list=LL_RY9p6Xwh55mWLYHK9Dw3g&amp;index=2">All Aboard the Elixir Express! by Chris McCord</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.phoenixframework.org/">Pheonix Web Framework</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/sconover/wrong">Better assertion failure messages with the &ldquo;Wrong&rdquo; Gem</a></li>
<li><a href="http://elm-lang.org/">The Elm Language</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup May 13, 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/05/13/meetup-may-13/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-13T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyrb.github.io/posts/2015/05/13/meetup-may-13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/joelmeador">Joel Meador</a> - Ruby News</h3>

<p><a href="http://podcast.404dev.com/episodes/2015-05-Joel_Meador-Ruby_News.pdf">Slides</a></p>

<h3><a href="https://twitter.com/unixmonkey">David Jones</a> - Volt.rb</h3>

<p><a href="https://github.com/unixmonkey/volt_todos">Code</a> /
<a href="http://voltframework.com/">Volt Framework</a> /
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KbFtIt7-ge8">Building a Todo Tracking App in Volt in 10 minutes</a> /
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7i6AL7Walc4">Isomorphic App Development with Ruby and Volt by Ryan Stout</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
